{"name": "E23 2021-12", "questions": [{"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "1. For all nonzero values of x and y, which of the following expressions is equivalent to  ?", "choices": {"A": "-7x4y3", "B": "-7x5y4", "C": "-7x6y5", "D": "-30x4y3", "E": "-40x4y3"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "2. The degree measures of the 3 angles of the triangle below are expressed in terms of x. What is the value of x?", "choices": {"A": "10", "B": "12", "C": "24", "D": "30", "E": "36"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "3. A 48.5-ounce batch of cologne will be used to fill empty bottles. Each full bottle will contain 0.35 ounces of cologne. This batch of cologne will fill at most how many bottles full of cologne?", "choices": {"A": "13", "B": "14", "C": "122", "D": "138", "E": "139"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "4. Of the 200 parking spaces in a parking lot, 6% of the spaces are reserved for handicapped parking. Of those parking spaces NOT reserved for handicapped parking, 20 are suitable for compact cars only. How many spaces that are NOT reserved for handicapped parking are suitable for noncompact cars?", "choices": {"A": "160", "B": "168", "C": "174", "D": "180", "E": "188"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "5. What is the value of \uff1f", "choices": {"A": "-35", "B": "-27", "C": "-18", "D": "-8", "E": "-7"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "6. Ricardo started a savings account for his daughter Ruth by depositing $500 into the account for her 1st birthday. For each successive birthday, Ricardo deposits $200 more than the amount deposited for the previous birthday. This is the only money deposited into the account. What is the total amount of money Ricardo will have deposited into the account for Ruth up to and including her 6th birthday?", "choices": {"A": "$4,000", "B": "$4,200", "C": "$4,700", "D": "$4,900", "E": "$6,000"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "7. Tawanna bought a used car. She made an initial payment of $700.00. She then made 36 equal monthly payments. The total amount Tawanna paid for the car was $7,000.00. What was the amount of each of her monthly payments?", "choices": {"A": "$19.44", "B": "$175.00", "C": "$194.44", "D": "$213.89", "E": "$360.00"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "8. Which of the following matrices is equal to \uff1f", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "9. Lyle and Ming are painting an art room. They started with 4 gallons of paint. On the first day, Lyle used gallon of paint and Ming used  gallons of paint. How many gallons of paint were left when they completed their first day of painting?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "10. In the standard (x, y) coordinate plane, what is the slope of the line through (\u22123, 1) and (5, 6) ? ", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "11. The lengths of corresponding sides of 2 similar right triangles are in the ratio 4:5. The hypotenuse of the smaller triangle is 24 inches long. How many inches long is the hypotenuse of the larger triangle? ", "choices": {"A": "1.25", "B": "9", "C": "20", "D": "25", "E": "30"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "12. The lengths of the 3 sides of right triangle \u25b3ABC shown below are given in meters. What is sin A ? ", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "13. In the figure shown below, C is on the segment with endpoints A and D. The distance between A and B is 2,000 km, between A and C is 1,600 km, between A and D is 2,500 km, and between B and C is 1,200 km. What is the distance, in kilometers, between B and D ? ", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "900", "D": "1,200", "E": "1,500"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "14. What is the sum of the 2 solutions of the equation x2 \u2212 4x \u2212 45 = 0 ?", "choices": {"A": "-45", "B": "-5", "C": "0", "D": "4", "E": "9"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "15. In the figure shown below, all angles are right angles, and the side lengths given are in inches. What is the area, in square inches, of the figure? ", "choices": {"A": "42", "B": "57", "C": "67", "D": "89", "E": "99"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "16. Quadrant I of the standard (x, y) coordinate plane is shown on a large computer screen. A blinking dot is positioned at (2, 3). The dot makes exactly 2 moves: first, horizontally in the positive x direction for 4 seconds at a speed of 0.5 coordinate units per second; then, vertically in the positive y direction for 2 seconds at the same speed. At what point is the dot located after these 2 moves? ", "choices": {"A": "\uff082, 6\uff09", "B": "(3, 5)", "C": "(4, 4)", "D": "(5, 3)", "E": " (6, 5)"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "17. A weeklong summer camp is held in June for children in Grades 3\u22126. Parents and guardians who enrolled their children for camp by May 15 received a 20% discount off the regular enrollment fee for each child enrolled. For each grade, the table below gives the number of children enrolled by May 15 as well as the regular enrollment fee per child. The grade of any child is that child\u2019s grade in school as of May 15. By May 15, Mr. Ramirez had enrolled his 2 children for camp. One child was in Grade 4, and the other was in Grade 6. What was the total amount Mr. Ramirez paid to enroll his 2 children? ", "choices": {"A": " $720", "B": "$800", "C": "$820", "D": "$860", "E": " $880"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "18. A weeklong summer camp is held in June for children in Grades 3\u22126. Parents and guardians who enrolled their children for camp by May 15 received a 20% discount off the regular enrollment fee for each child enrolled. For each grade, the table below gives the number of children enrolled by May 15 as well as the regular enrollment fee per child. The grade of any child is that child\u2019s grade in school as of May 15. Which of the following equations gives a true relationship between the regular enrollment fee, f, and the grade, g, of any child enrolled in the camp?", "choices": {"A": "f = g + 50", "B": "f = 50g", "C": "f = 50g + 200", "D": "f = 50g + 300", "E": "f = 300g + 50"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "19. A weeklong summer camp is held in June for children in Grades 3\u22126. Parents and guardians who enrolled their children for camp by May 15 received a 20% discount off the regular enrollment fee for each child enrolled. For each grade, the table below gives the number of children enrolled by May 15 as well as the regular enrollment fee per child. The grade of any child is that child\u2019s grade in school as of May 15. By May 15, Ms. Chen had enrolled her 2 children for camp. One child was in Grade 3, and the other was in Grade 4. For each grade, the names of all the children enrolled by May 15 will be entered into a drawing for a free T-shirt. For each grade, 1 name will be randomly drawn. What is the probability that the names of both of Ms. Chen\u2019s children will be drawn? ", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "20. You drove 18 miles in 20 minutes at a constant speed and did NOT exceed the speed limit, given in miles per hour. Among the following, which is the lowest that the speed limit could have been?", "choices": {"A": "45", "B": "50", "C": "55", "D": "60", "E": "65"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "21. What value of x makes the equation  true?", "choices": {"A": "-4", "B": "4", "C": "27", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "22. The equation  gives the resistance, R, in terms of the power, P, and the current, I, of an electrical system. Which of the following expressions gives I in terms of P and R ? ", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": "PR"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "23. One welcome sign flashes every 8 seconds, and another welcome sign flashes every 12 seconds. At a certain instant, the 2 signs flash at the same time. How many seconds elapse until the 2 signs next flash at the same time? ", "choices": {"A": "4", "B": "10", "C": "20", "D": "24", "E": "96"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "24. The area of a certain square is 900 square inches. What is the perimeter of this square, in inches?", "choices": {"A": "30", "B": "60", "C": "120", "D": "225", "E": "450"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "25. The Department of Natural Resources (DNR) is estimating the deer population in Twin Pines County. Several months ago, DNR rangers captured, tagged, and then released 108 deer. Recently, DNR rangers captured 54 deer in the county and found that 36 of them had been tagged in the earlier capture. The DNR estimates the deer population in the county using the proportion below. What is the DNR estimate of the deer population in the county? ", "choices": {"A": "108", "B": "126", "C": "144", "D": "162", "E": "198"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "26. In an arithmetic sequence, the 10th term (a10) is 30 and the common difference is 2. What is the 1st term (a1) ?", "choices": {"A": "-28", "B": "6", "C": "11", "D": "12", "E": "15"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "27. A pedometer records the number of steps a person takes as he or she walks. When a pedometer records 3,898 steps taken by a person who covers a distance of 2.25 feet per step, how much distance, to the nearest 0.1 mile, did the person cover?(Note: 1 mile = 5,280 feet)", "choices": {"A": "0.3", "B": "0.6", "C": "1.4", "D": "1.7", "E": "3.0"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "28. Among a group of 20 students, 13 students are members of the Math Club, 11 students are members of the Drama Club, and 9 students are members of both clubs. How many of the 20 students are NOT members of either club?", "choices": {"A": " 4", "B": "5", "C": "6", "D": "11", "E": "13"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "29. To increase the mean of 7 numbers by 4, by how much would the sum of the 7 numbers have to increase?", "choices": {"A": "4", "B": "7", "C": "11", "D": "28", "E": "56"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "30. Which of the following is an equation of the circle in the standard (x, y) coordinate plane whose center is at (4, \u22123) and whose radius is 5 coordinate units long?", "choices": {"A": " (x - 4)2 + (y + 3)2 = 5", "B": "(x - 4)2 + (y + 3)2 = 25", "C": "(x - 3)2 + (y + 4)2 = 25", "D": "(x + 3)2 + (y - 4)2 = 5", "E": "(x + 4)2 + (y - 3)2 = 25"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "31. All 25 students in a chemistry class took a test. Each student earned a test score that was an integer number of points, and no 2 students earned the same test score. The median test score was 80 points. How many students earned a test score that was greater than 80 points? ", "choices": {"A": "5", "B": "12", "C": "13", "D": " 14", "E": "20"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "32. Shefali goes to a farmers\u2019 market every Saturday. Two Saturdays ago, Shefali purchased 3 apples and 4 oranges for a total of $3.47. Last Saturday, she purchased 12 oranges, but no apples, and spent $6.36. Today, she only has one $10 bill. Given that none of the prices have changed over the last 3 weeks, what is the maximum number of apples she can purchase today?(Note: No sales tax is charged at this farmers\u2019 market.)", "choices": {"A": "18", "B": "19", "C": "21", "D": "22", "E": "23"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "33. Fletcher purchased 5 items at Hippity-Bippity Toy Store for a total of $18.55, which included sales tax. When he arrived home, he discovered that his receipt was torn and did not show the price of the bag of balloons or the 6% sales tax applied to the sum of the 5 prices. The partial receipt is shown below. Fletcher left his home 1 hour 15 minutes before he entered the store. He spent 25 minutes in the store before he made his purchase. What time did Fletcher leave his home?", "choices": {"A": "12:50 p.m.", "B": "1:10 p.m.", "C": "1:20 p.m.", "D": "1:30 p.m.", "E": "1:40 p.m."}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "34. Fletcher purchased 5 items at Hippity-Bippity Toy Store for a total of $18.55, which included sales tax. When he arrived home, he discovered that his receipt was torn and did not show the price of the bag of balloons or the 6% sales tax applied to the sum of the 5 prices. The partial receipt is shown below. To the nearest $0.10, what was the price of the bag of balloons? ", "choices": {"A": " $1.10", "B": "$2.40", "C": "$2.50", "D": "$2.70", "E": "$3.50"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "35. Fletcher purchased 5 items at Hippity-Bippity Toy Store for a total of $18.55, which included sales tax. When he arrived home, he discovered that his receipt was torn and did not show the price of the bag of balloons or the 6% sales tax applied to the sum of the 5 prices. The partial receipt is shown below. The price of the doll was how much greater than the mean of the 4 prices shown on the partial receipt? ", "choices": {"A": " $1.50", "B": "$2.00", "C": "$2.25", "D": "$2.50", "E": " $3.00"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "36. Fletcher purchased 5 items at Hippity-Bippity Toy Store for a total of $18.55, which included sales tax. When he arrived home, he discovered that his receipt was torn and did not show the price of the bag of balloons or the 6% sales tax applied to the sum of the 5 prices. The partial receipt is shown below. Malik will spend a total of $30.00 before sales tax on x bags of marbles and y cars purchased at the prices shown on the partial receipt. One of the following line segments graphed in the standard (x, y) coordinate plane contains points for all possible combinations of x and y. Which one? ", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "37. In \u25b3DEF, shown in the figure below, EG is an altitude, \u2220DEF is a right angle, EF = 20 centimeters, and the measure of \u2220EDF is 30\u00b0. What is EG, in centimeters?", "choices": {"A": "10", "B": "", "C": "20", "D": "", "E": "40"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "38. Let the polynomial functions f and g be defined as f(x) = x2 + 7x \u2212 3 and g(x) = x2 \u2212 4x + 5. Let h(x) = f(x) \u2212 g(x). What is h(2) ?", "choices": {"A": "-16", "B": "8", "C": "14", "D": "22", "E": "24"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "39. A student is using a protractor, as shown below, to find the measures of the interior angles of \u25b3ABC. Which of the following is closest to the degree measure of \u2220C ?", "choices": {"A": "36\u00b0", "B": "44\u00b0", "C": "46\u00b0", "D": "54\u00b0", "E": "66\u00b0"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "40.  For real numbers x and y such that 0 \u2264 x \u2264 5 and y \u2265 9, the expressioncan have which of the following values?", "choices": {"A": "0", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "5", "E": "6"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "41. Given the functions f(x) = x2 + 1 and g(x) = x \u2212 3, which of the following expressions is f(g(x)) ?", "choices": {"A": "x2 - 8", "B": "x2 - 6x + 10", "C": "x2 + x - 2", "D": "x2 + x - 3", "E": "x3 - 3x2 + x - 3"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "42. Given that the equation  is true, what is the value of ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "43. Juro traveled to 3 locations during a workday. Juro remained at each location a whole number of hours. The graph below shows the relationship between time, in hours, into his workday and total distance, in kilometers, traveled. Which of the following values is closest to Juro\u2019s average speed, in kilometers per hour, for the parts of the workday when he was traveling?", "choices": {"A": "45", "B": "57", "C": "60", "D": "75", "E": "94"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "44. What is the amplitude of the function y = 3 sin x ?", "choices": {"A": "1", "B": "3", "C": "6", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "45. For all nonzero values of w, which of the following expressions is equivalent to ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "46. Let A, B, and C represent the digits in the hundreds, tens, and ones places, respectively, of a certain 3-digit whole number. Let D, E, and F represent the digits in the hundreds, tens, and ones places, respectively, of a different 3-digit whole number. The positive difference between the 2 numbers is greater than 100. Which of the following inequalities must be true?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "A - D \u2265 1", "E": "B - E \u2265 1"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "47. A number line graph includes the points at real numbers a and b, as shown below. Which of the following inequalities expresses an interval that must include the product ab ?", "choices": {"A": "-1 \uff1c ab \uff1c a", "B": "a \uff1c ab \uff1c 0", "C": "0 \uff1c ab \uff1c b", "D": "b \uff1c ab \uff1c 1", "E": "1 \uff1c ab \uff1c 2"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "48. Sani\u2019s course grade in his chemistry class is based on 3 tests and 1 final exam. Each of the 3 test scores is weighted as 20% of the course grade, and the final exam score is weighted as 40% of the course grade. Sani\u2019s 3 test scores are 78, 86, and 82, respectively. What is the minimum score that Sani will have to earn on the final exam in order to receive a course grade of at least 86 ?", "choices": {"A": "82", "B": "84", "C": "90", "D": "92", "E": "98"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "49. The triangle below has vertices A(\u22121,\u22122), B(2,2), and C(\u22121,4). What is the area of \u25b3ABC, in square coordinate units?", "choices": {"A": "9", "B": "15", "C": "18", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "50. For some real number x, . Therefore x is: ", "choices": {"A": " zero.", "B": "greater than \u03c0. ", "C": " irrational.", "D": "negative.", "E": "undefined."}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "51. In the standard (x, y) coordinate plane below, point A has coordinates (2,\u22124), and point B(8,\u22121) divides AC so that the ratio AB:BC is 1:3. What are the coordinates of point C ?", "choices": {"A": "(-16, -13)", "B": "(10, 0)", "C": "(14, 2)", "D": "(26, 8)", "E": "(32, 11)"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "52. A wire binds 4 identical posts together as shown below. Each post has a 3-inch radius. What is the length, to the nearest inch, of the shortest wire that will go around the 4 posts without overlap? ", "choices": {"A": "21", "B": "31", "C": "33", "D": "43", "E": "52"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "53. Given that b is rational and , the product of the expression (3 + bi) and which of the following expressions must be a rational number? ", "choices": {"A": " i", "B": "bi", "C": "3bi", "D": "3 + bi", "E": "3 - bi"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "54. For positive integers x and y where x &lt; 8, logx8 = y. What is the value of y ?", "choices": {"A": "1", "B": "2", "C": "3", "D": "4", "E": "8"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "55. The right triangle shown below is 8 squares high and 10 squares long. One of the following values is the ratio of the shaded area to the unshaded area. Which one? ", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "56. For all positive integers x, which of the following expressions is equivalent to ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "57. One day on the New York Currency Exchange, 1 British pound (\u00a31) could be exchanged for $2.75 in U.S. currency, and 1 Canadian dollar ($1) could be exchanged for $0.92 in U.S. currency. On that day, how much Canadian currency, rounded to the nearest Canadian cent, could be exchanged for \u00a32 ?", "choices": {"A": "$0.41", "B": "$1.84", "C": "$2.07", "D": "$5.06", "E": "$5.98"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "58. The sides of an acute triangle measure 17 cm, 16 cm, and 15 cm, respectively. The measure of the smallest angle of the triangle is a solution for A to which of the following equations?", "choices": {"A": "172 = 152 + 162 - 2(15)(16)sin A", "B": "172 = 152 + 162 - 2(15)(16)cos A", "C": "162 = 152 + 172 - 2(15)(17)cos A", "D": "152 = 162 + 172 - 2(16)(17)sin A", "E": "152 = 162 + 172 - 2(16)(17)cos A"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "59. Set A and Set B each consist of 5 distinct numbers. The 2 sets contain identical numbers with the exception of the number with the least value in each set. The number with the least value in Set B is greater than the number with the least value in Set A. The value of which of the following measures must be greater for Set B than for Set A ?", "choices": {"A": "Mean only", "B": "Median only", "C": "Range only", "D": "Mean and range only", "E": "Mean, median, and range"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "60.  Of the 16 cars on a rental-car lot, 6 are minivans, 7 are sedans, and 3 are hatchbacks. Thalia will rent 3 of these cars, chosen at random, for business associates. What is the probability that Thalia will rent 1 of each of the 3 types of cars?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "D"}]}